for the following reason.  Eh, you're an
old-schooler, but in an old-school way
, although you don't have an
intermodular project, you have a TFG and the index and
in the theme of the
intermodular project.  Wait a minute.
And
yes, yes, correct.  But look, I'll tell you.
Wait, wait, Fran, just a moment.  I'm
going to show it with the calendar and we'll
see it better there.  One moment.
Let's see,
calendar.  Let's take it out here.  Let's get
DAM out.  Okay, the thing is,
we had this, okay?  We had an
intermodular project from 1:30 to 2:30, okay?  And
then we had 15 to 5, okay?  It's
actually 3 hours, so this is
what we were doing until now,
which is an intermodular project for
one hour and business management systems for
2 hours.  The idea is to do it
like this, okay?  So that's still 3
hours.  The difference is that instead of
doing an hour here and 2 hours
there, we do the 3 hours in a row.   That
is, the hours, which in fact I am
not in a particular hurry beyond the
Ah, sorry, sorry.  No, no, no, no, no,
no.  Yeah, yeah, yeah.  Ah,
in the Let's see, on paper, wait.  In
what role?
In the notepad.
Ah, this, uh, no,
wait, what I'm
writing is also wrong, okay?  Because that's how it is.
So.
Okay, so four is not,
from 16 to 18 is two and from 18 to 19 is
one, okay?  There are three of them, but I don't
care.  I mean, even if there were
four of them, it wouldn't be a problem.  That is,
as long as there are no fewer, there is no
problem.  Well, if there's more, then
fine, of course.  And if there are more, then better.   I
mean, what's more, what's more,
I'm almost certain that tomorrow's class won't
end at 7, I mean, it will
probably end at 8, mainly
because there are things to talk about tomorrow.
I mean, tomorrow there's everything to
show, tomorrow there's everything to unravel, and
if, uh, tomorrow we start at 4 and at 6 we
're still unraveling everything, then
we'll keep unraveling everything, okay?  I
mean, it's not a matter of, oh, no, it's
over, so we'll cut it off, okay?  I mean, I'm
telling you.  So that's it.  So, going back
to
Miguel Ángel's question, Miguel Ángel, my
recommendation is that you attend, okay?  For
a very simple reason,
the issue of FSTs, now in-
company training, is a pain, isn't it?  Because
before, we used to send students to FCT
in March when they already had all the
training, which is your case, okay?  Stop
because you're old school, which
was cool.  But it must be said
that since the TFG project was produced in the
last 3 months while you were doing your
internship, of course, the project didn't
have real monitoring and tutoring
or project classes. Instead,
each tutor gives the
project index and says, "Okay, guys, go
for it."  Okay, what's going on?  Just
as I don't like the new features in the internships
, I do like the new features in what
used to be the TFG, which is now an
intermodular project for those in the new plan,
because there are hours assigned
during the week to talk about that
topic and to work on the project,
okay?  And the index is
practically the same.  So for that
reason, I, Miguel Ángel, absolutely
invite you to attend and finish
the recordings and all that, because it's not like it's
going to be something different, I would
tell you, Miguel, don't waste your time
because what
you have to deliver is going to be different, but it's
practically the same, okay?
So, I'm telling you, my recommendation is that if you
want to start now with the
rest of the new plan students, even if you
submit it in June, that's also
fine.  Okay, so, for me it's
great.  I'll have to evaluate the rest of the students
quarterly, and in
your case, I'll save the grade for
June, okay?  Because the students of the
new plan, eh intermodular project 2, are
evaluated by quarters and such.  By the
way, I talked about it before, Fran, with Alicia and
with Pilar, who already
told me that, well, they didn't know that there are
three quarters in second period,
okay?  asks for nothing.  Now then it's that I did
n't want to talk too much with
them either because the first-year students were waiting for me
, okay?  But now I'll
tell you the plan later.  But they already
told me that they told you two
quarters and that you said, "No, no, it's that
José Vicente told us that it's
three, okay? That I have to talk to
them and inform them of how this issue is going
and all that, okay? And uh Luis, well
tell you the idea, tell you the idea and let's go
for it.
Well, I'll tell you, I'll tell you better
here. Of course,
look, basically it's uh creating a
software, an application. In any case,
at first I'm going to do it from the
cloud, that is, like we're doing
now for the website, but the idea is to
do it for Android and iOS. Well, it's going to be
a complicated one, but oh well, because the
application is basically a management of
employees of a restaurant, because
my partner works at Volterita and he
tells me that they use an application
called, I can tell you
right now, that it's a What's the name of the
application?
Ah, I'll tell you in a second.
Well, I'll tell you now because my
cell phone is off, but but basically yes,
but basically he tells me that it works
quite poorly
because, for example, when  They upload, uh, the
PDF of some information or
whatever, you can't, for example,
rotate the screen or whatever. She
tells me that some messages don't
arrive, that the
real-time update is a little slow, etc.
And basically she tells me that the
application is not very intuitive to
use. So I got the idea
that precisely since my partner works at a
restaurant, at Voltereta, I
said, "Why don't I try to
make an application like that?" But
since she tells me all the errors or
everything that she sees wrong, being a
person outside the world of programming, who
is basically the end user, well,
maybe it would be a good idea
for a project. I'm looking for you
right now exactly what it's called
in case you want to look it up now. I think it's
called I think it's called Mapal One.
Mapal,
Mapal, yes, Mapal One is what it's called. Okay,
Apple One, okay.
It's that one
because she tells me that it works
quite poorly and I looked it up on Apple, on
the Apple Store, that is, yes, on  The
Play Store, sorry. And it has a 1.9
review score, so it's going to be average.
Perfect.
So, of course, I said, "Wow, it
could be
a good option for creating
software development, and maybe even
suggesting it so they can
use it in that
restaurant, too." Well, that would be more or less
the ideal scenario.
Perfect.  Okay, let's see, let's
move forward with that idea, okay?
Let's move forward with that
project,
okay?  And I'm going to put a small
but to you, which is the following.
Hey, more than a but, I'm going to give you a
task to do.  You see, a few
years ago I attended a talk by this person
that I'm going to tell you about here, okay?  who is
Javier Echalecu, who is an entrepreneur,
works in marketing, is well-known in
Valencia, let's say, in the world of
marketing, entrepreneurship and all
that.  And this person at one point,
a few years ago, was giving a talk and
I was there as a listener, well,
enjoying the talk, right?  Then he
told us something that made us all
start laughing because in his
talks he tells you about his
business failures, but he tells you about them in a
funny way, okay?  People laugh,
but then when you look at the message
underneath it's a very dramatic message.
And then he said that years ago he was a
supplier to Mercadona with a
footwear company that he owned and the one in which he
was a partner and in
Mercadona, El Corte Inglés.  And then
at El Corte Inglés, on the
loading dock, every time he went or went with
a partner or a delivery person went to send
an order, to deliver an order, well, he
said that on the loading dock, since
there are drafts, the paper delivery note
, right?, he would
pin it on a pin, which is a
fairly common practice, especially it
's an old practice to ensure
that when on a loading dock that
's half open to air, when a
supplier brings a delivery note, you pin it
on the pin so the air can't
carry it away.  It is a very basic technique,
but very effective in not losing
Baranes.  And then he came up with the idea of
making an app.  He doesn't know how to
program, but he hired a kid to
basically create a software
for managing invoices at the
reception point, in the warehouse.  And then, of
course, since he was a supplier to
Mercadona, to Mercadona del Corte
Inglés, he had the contacts to
request a meeting, to arrange a meeting with
half the bosses, half the bigwigs, half the
decision-makers, right?  and
introduce them to the software.  So,
he got that meeting, made the
presentation, the skewer was in the presentation
, as an example
of what's old and what's not, okay?
And then the guy said in the talk
that at the end of the presentation, the people at El
Corte Inglés said, "Hey, this is very
good, what you presented to us is super
cool, it's very good, but we didn't
ask for it."
So, of course, the guy said
that he suddenly stopped and
said, "Yeah, I mean, you didn't actually
ask me, this was
my initiative, but I think that
with the stick I could, I mean, I mean, without
the stick, with the software you could
work better."  And the guy said, and we
all burst out laughing
because he said it as a joke, that
the people who were at the meeting
said, "Yeah, but we don't
have any problem with the pincho."
That is to say, no, no employee of El
Corte Inglés has complained about the snack.
This is you, as a provider, who
thought we might need an
app, but we don't
need an app because
the spike works for us.  And the guy said that he
left the meeting and said, "I've wasted
six months, not of my life, but
paying the programmer for something that El
Corte Inglés hadn't asked for at all
and that El Corte Inglés didn't see as a
need. Okay? With this, what I'm
telling you is that, in other words, you're
telling me about the need of an
end user,
but that user isn't the
decision maker, but nevertheless, I'm sure that
user can put you in contact
with the decision maker, okay? I
mean, I'm not saying no, but I
'm telling you this story so that the
same thing doesn't happen to you as this person and
that you spend six months now
working on a project and then
Voltereta comes along and says, "That's cool, but I don't
want it because I didn't ask you for it."
Okay? So the question is, it
sounds to me that Voltereta is a
company that has several
restaurants, so I understand that there
must be a central office that makes these types
of decisions to apply them to all the
Volteretas.  that there are, because as I'm
telling you, I think there are, at least in
Valencia, two or three. The question,
okay?, that you have to ask your
partner is if there is some way to
avoid unpleasantness, eh, apart from her
being clear that she has objectively
justified that this software has
deficiencies,
if she can contact the person who
makes the decisions or someone close to the
decision-maker to see to what
extent the company is offered a
better alternative, if the company is
willing or receptive to considering
better offers, okay? In terms of
functionality, in terms of price, in
terms of whatever. And only if that
consultation is positive, then I'll tell you,
go program that application,
okay? And if the company says, "Well, of
course, we already have this
implemented, changing this implementation
would be a big deal," and go, you know?  And if they
put up a fight, I'd say, don't bang your
head against the wall programming
something for a company that's already
telling you they won't buy it.
Another issue, obviously, is that you don't
design the application with
Voltereta's specific rules, but rather that
you try to design the application with
the most generic rules possible so
that in case Voltereta tells you
no, then you say, "No
problem, I'll go to the rest, but not to the rest,
I'll go to the [ __ ] rest of the restaurants in
all of Valencia and all of Spain to
offer them what Voltereta didn't
want.
Okay, so that's why I'm saying it.
Of course, I'm saying it for Sure,
yes, tell me.
Let's see, yes, let's see, the uh really the
idea yes uh
the ideal would be to create it as a
service, I mean, like not
everything is like an application designed
only for Voltereta, I mean, that it's
like super everything Voltereta, because maybe
that would be if they told me
that they wanted it only for them, which would be
super cool, but oh well.
Uh, so the idea is that, to do it
as a service and then if they really want it,
well, look, but
obviously and I think  Yes, I do think I
could try to get in touch with
Perfecto. Make a decision
and or or close. I think I could
try. Yes,
well, look, I'm
telling you, move it
more than anything to know that, I mean,
if you start working on it,
at least there are possibilities, you
know? Good. And then and then, uh, not at
a business level, but at a
more technological level,
uh, we'll get to the teaching units
corresponding to
application programming. And from there I
will tell you that in previous years, uh, I
mean, I have been teaching students
a mix of application creation
based on web technologies that
become native applications.
Uh, and then, obviously, I can't
teach iOS because I would have to have a
Mac and I would have to force you all to
have a Mac. Uh, but Android yes, in
previous years what I have done is
reserve a part of the syllabus for
Cotlin and XML, okay? since
native programming in Android works with
Cotlin in the drivers, XML uh in
the views, XML for what HTML and
CSS would do, let's say, styles and structure and
then a mix between that and something
similar to local storage inside, that
is, to persist data, okay? and of
course asynchronous communications with
a server for
API consumption and all that. This year I'm
not even going to bother with that, I mean, I
'm going to skip over the Cotlin part very, very
briefly and we're going to go directly to
web technologies. Why? Well, to
web technologies that later become
mobile applications. Why? Well,
because you can spend a
lot of time on Android and then that's worth
absolutely nothing on iOS because
iOS is another platform that works with Swift
and on top of that, now they're commenting that
if they want to change Swift for another
language, I mean, it's crazy. Okay? So
, the idea is that we'll
be working with layout and
web technologies,
obviously avoiding removing the entire
PHP and MySQL part because it's not
applicable for obvious reasons, right? And
so, the advantage of that is
that layouts  the application once and
then you deploy it to both Android
and iOS without having to reprogram the
application multiple times, okay? But that's what it's all about
. That's what it's all about
. Indeed, Fran.
Okay, so I'll tell you, well,
let's get to it. We'll keep moving forward,
but as I said,
can I interrupt you?
Sure, sure.
Look, here I think I don't know if it's
complicated to do this type of
application or script. In this case, I
think it's because, look, I'll give you a
real example. Right now at
work at McDonald's, they ask us to do
some reviews
by scanning a QR code.
Yes.
And what happens? Okay, this is a bit, it
's not confidential, but hey, I don't
care. It's the thing about
listen, listen, I'm recording. If
you want, I'll stop.
Stop it, stop it, stop it.